# **Kavin Varnan**

Experienced Full Stack Team leader possessing excellent technical architecting skills and problem solving in software development. My area of specialisation is architecting mobile applications and backend servers.

10th A Main Road, Indiranagar, Bangalore +91 97907 00016 skavinvarnan@gmail.com https://skvarnan.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Ather Energy,** Bangalore — *Manager*

MAY 2019 - PRESENT

- Involved in developing the customer facing website and its equivalent Backend server
- Managing the devops
- Worked on the charging infrastructure for Ather vehicles

## **Invaria Tech**, Bangalore — Technical Lead

MAY 2016 - APRIL 2019

- Technical lead for NodeJS and Android team
- Design, Architect and development of backend and mobile application
- Involved in Requirement analysis and complete DevOps architecture including clustering
- Travelled on-site couple of times

## **TAAL Tech**, Bangalore — Software Engineer

AUGUST 2015 - APRIL 2016

- Worked on Android application and backend server using NodeJS, SailsJS and MongoDB
- Built a basic CRM portal using SailsJS

# **Virtual Applets,** Chennai — Co Founder

JANUARY 2013 - AUGUST 2015

- Responsible for technical architecture of projects
- Worked on various Android, iOS, IOT and Cloud apps
- Had experience in finding, meeting and closing deals with clients
- Travelled on-site for client visit

# **Tringapps,** Chennai — Research Analyst

JANUARY 2012 - JANUARY 2013

- Worked on Android mobile and tablet apps
- Worked on Android UI extensively

#### REPUTATION

<u>Stackoverflow</u> - 1580+ Github stars - 85+

#### **CORE TECHNICAL SKILLS**

## Languages

- NodeJS (es5 and es6)
- Java
- Kotlin
- Embedded C
- Swift

#### Backend

- NodeIS
- ExpressJS
- SailsJS
- Message broker
  - Google Pub/Sub
  - MQTT
  - RabbitMQ
- Spring and Spring Boot
- Hibernate
- PM2

#### **Databases**

- MongoDB
- Redis
- Google BigQuery
- MySQL

#### Android

- Kotlin
- RESTFul API's
- BLE
- Jetpack Navigation
- Backend services
- Material design

### **PROJECTS**

## Willowpump — Feb 2018 - Present

Managed Software product life-cycle and development activities of app-based application.

Technologies used for this project – NodeJS, ExpressJS, Google PubSub, Kubernetes, Docker, Microservices, Firebase, Salesforce, Shopify, Electron, BLE, kotlin.

## **Proxfinity** — *May* 2016 - *Feb* 2018

Involved in developing Android apps and backend server from scratch.

Technologies used for this project - Android, BLE, Parse Server, Angular JS, SailsJS, Azure App Service, MongoDB

## vCarrot — September 2015 - April 2016

Ported the existing iOS app to Android and feature implementation for iOS. Built a basic CRM tool using SailsJS

Technologies used for this project - Android, iOS (Swift), NodeJS, SailsJS, RESTFul, MongoDB

## **DiodeOne** — July 2014 - September 2015

Created the complete project ecosystem

Technologies used for this project – Android, iOS, AngularJS 1.4, ESP8266, ESP32, MQTT, Bluetooth, WiFI, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB Mosquito, SonOFF

# Indulgge — August 2013 - June 2014

Created the Android app and backend server

Technologies used for this project - Android, AngularJS 1.4, Spring, Hibernate, MySQL, RESTFul

## **HBO GO** — *May* 2012 - *January* 2013

Worked on UI and basic business logic

Technologies used for this project - Android Tablet UI, Mobile UI, JSON Processing

# Time Mobile — January 2012 - May 2012

Worked on UI and basic business logic

Technologies used for this project - RestFul API's, Authenticate API's, XML processing

## **DevOps**

- Docker
- Docker Swarm
- Kubernetes
- AWS
- Google Cloud Platform
- DigitalOcean
- Linode
- Azure (Only App Service)

#### TOT

- ESP8266
- ESP32
- PlatformIO

## **Documentation Tools**

- IIRA
- Confluence
- ClickUp
- Gitlab

### Other

- iOS architecture skills
- Electron based webapps
- React and Angular architecture skills
- Firebase
- Facebook Parse Server

#### **OPEN SOURCE**

- <u>Cross Platform AES</u> library on Github with 70+ stars
- <u>CryptoLib on NPM</u> with 5000+ downloads

## **OTHER SKILLS**

- Developing and timely delivery of working software that meets standards
- Good problem solving ability to break development hindrances
- Prioritizing programming work and task management accordingly
- Hosting meetings and having timely team interaction for smooth functioning of development process

#### **PERSONAL APPS**

- 1. Vault 10,000+ downloads
- 2. Galley 500,000+ downloads
- 3. IOT hobby project running successfully for 1+ years

#### **EDUCATION**

**REC**, Chennai — BE

SEPTEMBER 2007 - APRIL 2011

KVS Matric, Virudhunagar — School

## **LANGUAGES**

English, Tamil